Guide to the Army Specialized Training Division, Yale University, Records
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
Army Specialized Training Division, Yale University, records
1940-1963
RU 89
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
21
The records consist of correspondence, transcripts, photographs, instructional materials, and administrative files documenting the Army Specialized Training Division at Yale, particularly the Army Specialized Training Program (ASTP) and the Civil Affairs Specialists Training School.
Army Specialized Training Division (Yale University)
General note
Forms part of Yale Record Group 42-A (YRG 42-A), Records of military training programs at Yale.
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are partially restricted. See inventory for details.
Arrangement
The records are arranged by accession.
Biographical / Historical
The Army Training Schools, comprising the Civil Affairs Specialists Training School, the Military Intelligence Service Language School, and the Army Specialized Training Program, were established at Yale in 1943. The curricula was prescribed by the Army but administered by Yale.
Scope and Contents
The records consist of correspondence, transcripts, photographs, instructional materials, and administrative files documenting the Army Specialized Training Division at Yale, particularly the Army Specialized Training Program (ASTP) and the Civil Affairs Specialists Training School.
Military education -- United States; Military training camps -- United States; Soldiers -- Education, Non-military -- United States; Universities and colleges -- Administration; World War, 1939-1945 -- Education and the war; World War, 1939-1945 -- War work -- Schools; World War, 1939-1945 -- United States; Army Specialized Training Division (Yale University); Army Specialized Training Program (U.S.); Yale University -- Administration; Yale University -- Students
- Administrative files and student records, circa 1944-1946; Accession 19ND-A-169
  Conditions Governing Access
  Restricted until Jan 1, 2022
  - General files
    - Correspondence, circa 1944-1946 (Box 1)
    - Class lists, circa 1944-1946 (Box 1)
    - Record cards for students, circa 1944-1946 (Box 1)
    - Records of Staff Officers Asiatic Studies Course, Spring 1946 (Box 1)
  - Student transcript records with photographs
    - A-P (Box 2)
    - R-Z (Box 3)
  - A.S.T.P. premedical students (Box 3)
  - Student records, 1944-1945 (Box 4)
- Records, circa 1940-1963; Accession 19ND-A-170
  - Army Specialized Training Program, General
    - Advisoy Committee: Foreign Area and Language Training, 1943 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Area and Language Studies, 1944 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Aural Comprehension Test, 1943-1944 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Beukema, Herman, 1942-1944 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Carroll, Richard C., 1943-1946 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Chicago Conference, 1943 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Company A: Roster of Japanese, Russian, Burmese, Mayalan students, 1943 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Company E: Roster of Italian and Russian students, 1943 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Company F: Japanese students, 1943 (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - Contracts, 1943-1944 (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - Correspondence, general, 1942-1945 (Box 1, Folder 11 - 15)
    - Correspondence re Congress on Informants, 1946 (Box 1, Folder 16)
    - Course materials, 1943-1944 (Box 1, Folder 17)
    - Curriculum, 1943-1946 (Box 1, Folder 18 - 20)
    - Data, 1946 (Box 2, Folder 21)
    - First Service Command, 1943-1945 (Box 2, Folder 22)
    - Foreign Area and Language Studies, 1942-1944 (Box 2, Folder 23)
    - Grades, 1944-1945 (Box 2, Folder 24)
    - Headquarters, Army Training School, 1943-1945 (Box 2, Folder 25)
    - Honor list, 1943-1945 (Box 2, Folder 26)
    - Howe, William, 1944-1946 (Box 2, Folder 27)
    - Italian course, 1943-1944 (Box 2, Folder 28)
    - Japan and the Pacific, Tests and schedules, 1943-1944 (Box 2, Folder 29)
    - Language Program application, 1945-1946 (Box 2, Folder 30)
    - Miscellaneous: memoranda, schedules
      - 1943-1944 (Box 2, Folder 31)
      - 1944-1946 (Box 2, Folder 32)
    - Personnel, 1943-1944 (Box 2, Folder 33)
    - Rooms and Schedules, 1946 (Box 2, Folder 34)
    - Review, 1943-1946 (Box 2, Folder 35)
    - Sample proofs, grade cards, 1946 (Box 2, Folder 36)
    - Service Bureau, 1945 (Box 2, Folder 37)
    - Term 7L, 1944 (Box 2, Folder 38)
    - Tests, 1945 (Box 2, Folder 39)
    - Zehrer, Frederick, 1946 (Box 2, Folder 40)
  - Civilian Affairs Training School
    These records are restricted until January 1, 2022.
    - Academic Credit: blank forms for transcript record, 1944-1945 (Box 3, Folder 1)
    - American Council of Learned Societies, 1942-1945 (Box 3, Folder 2-4)
    - Books, 1944 (Box 3, Folder 5)
    - Books - Publishers, 1945 (Box 3, Folder 6)
    - Boston University, 1943 (Box 3, Folder 7)
    - Budget, 1944-1946 (Box 3, Folder 8-9)
    - Bursary Committee, 1943-1944 (Box 3, Folder 10-11)
    - Chicago, 1944 (Box 3, Folder 12)
    - Chinese Language Officer's Course, 1946-1947 (Box 3, Folder 13)
    - Conference, 1945 January (Box 3, Folder 14)
    - Correspondence
      - A-H, 1944-1945 (Box 3, Folder 15)
      - I-Z, 1944-1945 (Box 3, Folder 16)
      - A-D, 1944-1945 (Box 3, Folder 17)
      - E-H, 1944-1945 (Box 3, Folder 18)
      - I-L, 1944-1945 (Box 3, Folder 19)
      - M-P, 1944-1945 (Box 3, Folder 20)
      - Q-U, 1944-1947 (Box 3, Folder 21)
      - V-Z, 1944-1945 (Box 3, Folder 22)
      - A-Z, 1945-1948 (Box 3, Folder 23)
      - A-Z, 1943-1950 (Box 3, Folder 24)
      - Miscellaneous, 1944 (Box 3, Folder 25)
      - Student, 1945-1950 (Box 3, Folder 26)
    - Course Materials
      - 1943 (Box 4, Folder 27-28)
      - 1944 (Box 4, Folder 29-30)
      - 1945 (Box 4, Folder 31)
    - Course Outlines, undated (Box 4, Folder 32)
    - Curriculum: Europe, 1942-1943 (Box 4, Folder 33)
    - Curriculum: Far East, 1944-1945 (Box 4, Folder 34-35)
    - Diploma blanks, undated (Box 5, Folder 36)
    - Europe, 1943-1944 (Box 5, Folder 37)
    - Far East I - Biographies, 1944 (Box 5, Folder 38)
    - Far East III - Biographies, undated (Box 5, Folder 39)
    - Far East V - Biographies, undated (Box 5, Folder 40)
    - Far East VII - Biographies, undated (Box 5, Folder 41)
    - Far East IV, First Service Command, reports to, 1945 (Box 5, Folder 42)
    - Far East: Personnel, 1944-1945 (Box 5, Folder 43)
    - Far East Program, History of, 1945 (Box 5, Folder 44)
    - Far East III - weekly reports, 1945 (Box 5, Folder 45)
    - Far East IV - weekly reports, 1945 (Box 5, Folder 46)
    - Far East V, VI - weekly reports, 1944 (Box 5, Folder 47)
    - Films and Film Scripts, 1944 (Box 6, Folder 48)
    - Flattery File, 1944-1945 (Box 6, Folder 49-50)
    - Fort Custer: general information, 1943 (Box 6, Folder 51)
    - Furniss, E. S. Provost, 1945-1946 (Box 6, Folder 52)
    - Geography 30a and 30b Tests, undated (Box 6, Folder 53)
    - Geography 35b: outline, tests, exams, undated (Box 6, Folder 54)
    - Geography 40a: outline for field work, undated (Box 6, Folder 55)
    - Geography 50a: East Asia Reading List, undated (Box 6, Folder 56)
    - Geography 105a, undated (Box 6, Folder 57)
    - Geography 202 - map reading, undated (Box 6, Folder 58)
    - G.I. Bill information on book purchases, undated (Box 6, Folder 59)
    - Gorman, Lt. Colonel R.N., 1944-1945 (Box 6, Folder 60-61)
    - Handbooks, Manuals, 1944 (Box 6, Folder 62)
    - Harvard, 1943 (Box 6, Folder 63)
    - History 42 - topics for essays, undated (Box 6, Folder 64)
    - History 42a List of terms and names, 1946 (Box 6, Folder 65)
    - History 42b Readings, final exam, 1948 (Box 6, Folder 66)
    - History of CATS, 1944 (Box 6, Folder 67)
    - Hyneman, Charles S. Chief, Training Branch: Correspondence and memoranda
      - 1943 (Box 6, Folder 68-69)
      - 1944 (Box 7, Folder 70)
    - Information for incoming classes, 1945 (Box 7, Folder 71)
    - Internal Relations Readings, 1946 September (Box 7, Folder 72)
    - Interviews: Class I, 1942-1943 (Box 7, Folder 73)
    - Interviews: Class IV, 1944 (Box 7, Folder 74)
    - Japanese School at Savage, 1944 (Box 7, Folder 75)
    - Japanese Social Organization
      - Article by Hules, Frederick S., undated (Box 7, Folder 76)
      - The "occupation face" of Japan, undated (Box 7, Folder 77)
      - "Themes in Japanese Culture" by Geoffrey Gorer, 1943 (Box 7, Folder 78)
    - Lectures on Japan, 1944 (Box 7, Folder 79)
    - Library, 1945 (Box 7, Folder 80)
    - Marines: Fitness reports, 1946 (Box 7, Folder 81)
    - Material Received, Report of, 1944-1945 (Box 7, Folder 82-83)
    - Memoranda and Correspondence to unit instructors and unit commanders, 1950 (Box 7, Folder 84)
    - Michigan, 1943 (Box 7, Folder 85-86)
    - Miller, Jessie I., 1944-1945 (Box 8, Folder 87)
    - Miscellaneous: memoranda, schedules, charts, forms, 1944 (Box 8, Folder 88)
    - Moulton, William G., 1944-1945 (Box 8, Folder 89)
    - Newspaper Clippings, 1944-1945 (Box 8, Folder 90)
    - "Organization Faculty and Record of Instruction" by A. Whitney Griswold, 1943 (Box 8, Folder 91)
    - Other CAT Schools, 1944 (Box 8, Folder 92)
    - Payroll: expenses, 1944-1945 (Box 8, Folder 93)
    - Personnel - Classes I-IV, 1943-1944 (Box 8, Folder 94-96)
    - Pittsburg Conference, 1943 November (Box 8, Folder 97)
    - Pittsburg University, 1943 (Box 8, Folder 98)
    - Political Science 63, 63b; International Relations 115b Reading List, 1948-1950 (Box 8, Folder 99)
    - Public Health (Outlines, curriculum), 1944-1945 (Box 8, Folder 100)
    - Public Health Seminars, 1945 (Box 8, Folder 101)
    - Publishers, 1944-1945 (Box 8, Folder 102)
    - Rating Forms
      - Class II, 1943 November - 1944 April (Box 9, Folder 103)
      - Class III, 1943 November - 1944 January (Box 9, Folder 104)
      - Area, Class IV, 1944 January (Box 9, Folder 105)
      - Language Class IV, 1944 January - 1944 April (Box 9, Folder 106)
      - Summary, Class IV, 1944 Feb, Apr, July - September (Box 9, Folder 107)
      - Summary, Far East Class I Final, 1944 July - 1945 January (Box 9, Folder 108)
      - Far East Class II Final, 1944 November - 1945 May (Box 9, Folder 109)
      - Summary, Far East Class II, 1944 November - 1945 February (Box 9, Folder 110)
      - Summary, Far East Class III Final, 1945 February - August (Box 10, Folder 111)
      - Summary, Far East Class III Tentative, 1945 Feh - May (Box 10, Folder 112)
      - Summary, Far East IV Final, 1945 July -August (Box 10, Folder 113)
    - Recommendations for Transfer, 1944 January - February (Box 10, Folder 114)
    - Reports to First Service Command
      - Class I, 1944 July - 1945 January (Box 10, Folder 115)
      - Class II, 1944 November - 1945 May (Box 10, Folder 116)
      - Class III, 1945 February - August (Box 10, Folder 117)
    - Report of the President's Committee on Foreign Area Studies, undated (Box 11, Folder 118)
    - Research in National Trade Problems, 1947 (Box 11, Folder 119)
    - Robinson, LT. Colonel H.E., 1944-1945 (Box 11, Folder 120)
    - Rosters (CATS), 1944-1945 (Box 11, Folder 121)
    - Savings and Mutual Lending Societies (HO) by Nyuyen Van Wink, undated (Box 11, Folder 122)
    - Schedules, undated (Box 11, Folder 123)
    - Schedules - Class I-VI, 1944-1945 (Box 11, Folder 124)
    - Schedules and Reports
      - Far East Class I, 1944-1945 (Box 11, Folder 125)
      - Far East Class II, 1944-1945 (Box 11, Folder 126)
    - School of Military Government, Charlottesville, Va., 1944-1945 (Box 11, Folder 127)
    - Sociology 135b: Test, undated (Box 11, Folder 128)
    - Southeast Asia Studies: Budget, 1949-1950 (Box 11, Folder 129)
    - Southeast Asia Studies: card index file, undated (Box 11, Folder 130)
    - Specialists
      - Charlottesville Conference, 1943 (Box 11, Folder 131)
      - Germany and West Europe, 1943 (Box 11, Folder 132)
      - Italy and the Meditterranean, 1943 (Box 11, Folder 133)
      - Stanford University, 1943 (Box 12, Folder 134)
    - Statistics of Classes, undated (Box 12, Folder 135)
    - Teaching Applications, 1944-1945 (Box 12, Folder 136)
    - Teaching Appointments, 1944 (Box 12, Folder 137)
    - Tests, 1945 (Box 12, Folder 138)
    - Transcripts of credits, requests for, 1951 (Box 12, Folder 139)
    - Transcripts: miscellaneous memoranda, 1943-1952 (Box 12, Folder 140)
    - Travel Expense Accounts, 1945 (Box 12, Folder 141)
    - Travel Expense reports, 1944-1945 (Box 12, Folder 142)
    - Treasurer and Treasurer's Office: L.G. Tighe, 1945-1946 (Box 12, Folder 143)
    - Van Wagenen, Major Richard, 1943 (Box 12, Folder 144)
    - Weekly Schedules: Europe, 1943-1944 (Box 12, Folder 145)
    - Western Reserve University, 1943 (Box 12, Folder 146)
  - Foreign Area Studies
    - Bursary Committee, 1945 (Box 13, Folder 1)
    - Correspondence
      - A-B, 1943-1944 (Box 13, Folder 2)
      - C-D, 1943-1944 (Box 13, Folder 3)
      - E-F, 1943-1944 (Box 13, Folder 4)
      - G-H, 1943-1944 (Box 13, Folder 5)
      - I-J, 1943-1944 (Box 13, Folder 6)
      - K-L, 1943-1944 (Box 13, Folder 7)
      - M-N, 1943-1944 (Box 13, Folder 8)
      - O-P, 1943-1944 (Box 13, Folder 9)
      - Q-R, 1943-1944 (Box 13, Folder 10)
      - S-T, 1943-1944 (Box 13, Folder 11)
      - U-W, 1943-1944 (Box 13, Folder 12)
      - X-Z, 1943-1944 (Box 13, Folder 13)
    - Courses and instructors required after the war, 1944 (Box 13, Folder 14)
    - Enlisted Reserve Assignment, 1944-1945 (Box 13, Folder 15)
    - Faculty worksheets, 1944 (Box 13, Folder 16)
    - Foreign-born, forms for, undated (Box 13, Folder 17)
    - Inquiries about courses, 1944-1945 (Box 13, Folder 18)
    - Japanese Language Specialist Norman, E.H., 1945 (Box 13, Folder 19)
    - Marines: Buck, N.S., Yale Navy Unit, 1944-1945 (Box 13, Folder 20)
    - Newspaper clippings, 1945 (Box 13, Folder 21)
    - Overseas Council, Incorporated: Franklin Field, 1945 (Box 13, Folder 22)
    - Personnel Security Questionnaires, 1944 (Box 14, Folder 23)
    - Postwar Foreign Area Studies Plan, 1946 (Box 14, Folder 24)
    - Readers' vouchers, 1944-1945 (Box 14, Folder 25)
    - Reading list, class of, 1950 (Box 14, Folder 26)
    - Readings on Japan, 1947 (Box 14, Folder 27)
    - Report of Committee, letters regarding, 1944-1945 (Box 14, Folder 28)
    - Report to the President, 1943-1945 (Box 14, Folder 29)
    - Russian Course, Committee on, undated (Box 14, Folder 30)
    - Selective Service, 1944 (Box 14, Folder 31)
    - Staff, 1944 (Box 14, Folder 32)
    - Studies in the Post War Curriculum, Committee on, undated (Box 14, Folder 33)
  - International Relations
    - Applications, 1945-1946 (Box 15, Folder 1)
    - Book list, 1945 (Box 15, Folder 2)
    - Carroll, Richard C., 1945 (Box 15, Folder 3)
    - Corbett, Percy, 1945-1946 (Box 15, Folder 4)
    - Data, 1945 (Box 15, Folder 5)
    - Examinations, undated (Box 15, Folder 6)
    - Fellowships, 1946 (Box 15, Folder 7)
    - Graduate School Registrar, 1946 (Box 15, Folder 8)
    - Inter-faculty correspondence, 1946 (Box 15, Folder 9)
    - Logan, R.F., 1945-1946 (Box 15, Folder 10)
    - Miscellaneous memoranda, 1946 (Box 15, Folder 11)
    - Recommendations, 1946 (Box 15, Folder 12)
    - Registrar's office, 1946 (Box 15, Folder 13)
    - Simpson, Hartley, 1945-1946 (Box 15, Folder 14)
    - Student correspondence, 1945-1946 (Box 15, Folder 15)
    - Van Dyke, Vernon, 1945 (Box 15, Folder 16)
    - Wolfers, Arnold, 1946 (Box 15, Folder 17)
  - Staff Officers School
    - Class I
      - Academic Program, information on, 1945 (Box 16, Folder 1)
      - Attendance records, September - Dec, undated (Box 16, Folder 2)
      - Curriculum, undated (Box 16, Folder 3)
      - Inspection report, 1945 (Box 16, Folder 4)
      - Library book list, 1946 (Box 16, Folder 5)
      - Library rules, 1945 (Box 16, Folder 6)
      - Lectures: topical outline, 1945 (Box 16, Folder 7)
      - Officers
        - Baker, Bazil L., LT. Colonel, 1946 (Box 16, Folder 8)
        - Bodner, Charles J., LT. Colonel, 1946-1948 (Box 16, Folder 9)
        - Buell, Kenneth E., Captain, 1947-1963 (Box 16, Folder 10)
        - Cowen, Edward T., LT. Colonel, undated (Box 16, Folder 11)
        - Culley, Frank J., Colonel, 1946-1949 (Box 16, Folder 12)
        - Davenport, Harold, Colonel, undated (Box 16, Folder 13)
        - Davis, Richard C., LT Colonel, undated (Box 16, Folder 14)
        - Ebel, Henry W., LT. Colonel, undated (Box 16, Folder 15)
        - Edward, Wesley B., LT, Colonel, 1948 (Box 16, Folder 16)
        - Gallogly, Lester H., LT. Colonel, 1946 (Box 16, Folder 17)
        - Green, Richardson, LT. Colonel, 1946 (Box 16, Folder 18)
        - Hoehl, Frances, Colonel, 1946 (Box 16, Folder 19)
        - Hudgins, Seth F., Colonel, 1950 (Box 16, Folder 20)
        - Johnson, Bayard, Colonel, 1945 (Box 16, Folder 21)
        - Kearns, Edwin B.J., Colonel, undated (Box 16, Folder 22)
        - Mann, John W., LT. Colonel, 1946 (Box 16, Folder 23)
        - Price, Terrill E., Colonel, 1946-1952 (Box 16, Folder 24)
        - Putnam, Walter B., Colonel, 1949-1950 (Box 16, Folder 25)
        - Roberts, Rankin IV, Colonel, undated (Box 16, Folder 26)
        - Scott, Richard L., Colonel, undated (Box 16, Folder 27)
        - Shaw, Ronald W., Colonel, 1946 (Box 16, Folder 28)
        - Stevens, John D., Colonel, 1963 (Box 16, Folder 29)
        - Stickman, William K., Colonel, 1945 (Box 16, Folder 30)
        - Sullivan, Robert B., LT. Colonel, 1957 (Box 16, Folder 31)
        - Southerland, Edwin M., Colonel, undated (Box 16, Folder 32)
        - Taylor, Thomas F., Colonel, 1946 (Box 17, Folder 33)
        - Thompson, Robert P., Colonel, undated (Box 17, Folder 34)
        - Wade, Arthur B., Colonel, undated (Box 17, Folder 35)
        - Wallis, Severn T., Colonel, undated (Box 17, Folder 36)
        - Watts, Harry L. Jr., Colonel, undated (Box 17, Folder 37)
        - Welty, Elmer B., LT. Colonel, 1949-1950 (Box 17, Folder 38)
        - Witt, Landon A., LT. Colonel, 1946, 1964 (Box 17, Folder 39)
      - Orientation material, 1945 (Box 17, Folder 40)
      - Rating reports, 1945 (Box 17, Folder 41)
      - Roster, 1945 (Box 17, Folder 42)
      - Schedules: weekly drafts, 1945 (Box 17, Folder 43)
    - Class II
      - Academic arrangements, 1946 (Box 17, Folder 44)
      - Announcements: Faculty, general, 1946 (Box 17, Folder 45)
      - Attendence records, January - April undated (Box 17, Folder 46)
      - Housing (Box 17, Folder 47)
      - Lectures: blackboard outlines, undated (Box 17, Folder 48)
      - Lectures: requests for payments, 1946 (Box 17, Folder 49)
      - Library list: St. Anthony Hall Part I and II, 1946 (Box 17, Folder 50)
      - Library rules, undated (Box 17, Folder 51)
      - Officers
        - Baumer, Donald H., LT. Colonel, 1946 (Box 17, Folder 52)
        - Blake, Corzielfus H., LT. Colonel, 1946 (Box 17, Folder 53)
        - Bledsoe, Hugh H., LT. Colonel, 1946 (Box 17, Folder 54)
        - Brannon, Dale D., Colonel, 1946 (Box 17, Folder 55)
        - Brawn, Alston Law, Captain, 1946 (Box 17, Folder 56)
        - Butler, Roy D. Colonel, 1946 (Box 17, Folder 57)
        - Cole, Hubert M., Colonel, 1946-1954 (Box 17, Folder 58)
        - Crocker, David R., LT. Colonel, 1946 (Box 17, Folder 59)
        - Cutler, Edward W., Captain, 1946 (Box 17, Folder 60)
        - Cutler, John M., Captain, 1946 (Box 17, Folder 61)
        - Donaldson, Harold B., LT. Colonel, 1946 (Box 17, Folder 62)
        - Emry, Edgar B., LT. Colonel, 1946 (Box 17, Folder 63)
        - Folkes, John G., LT. Colonel, 1946 (Box 17, Folder 64)
        - Galbraith, John M. Jr., Major, 1946 (Box 17, Folder 65)
        - Hampton, Thomas K., Colonel, 1946 (Box 17, Folder 66)
        - Hauck, Herman A., Colonel, 1946 (Box 17, Folder 67)
        - Henry, William J., LT. Colonel, 1946 (Box 17, Folder 68)
        - Hill, Carl R., LT, Colonel, 1946 (Box 17, Folder 69)
        - House, A. T., Jr. LT, Colonel, 1946 (Box 17, Folder 70)
        - Jung, Wing F., LT. Colonel, 1946 (Box 17, Folder 71)
        - Kernan, Melvin M., LT. Colonel, 1946 (Box 17, Folder 72)
        - Kruzel, Joseph H., LT. Colonel, 1946 (Box 17, Folder 73)
        - Longine, Mercer P., Captain, 1946 (Box 17, Folder 74)
        - MacWillie, Donald M., LT. Colonel, 1946 (Box 17, Folder 75)
        - McKerley, James A., LT. Colonel, 1946 (Box 17, Folder 76)
        - Miller, Allen C. II, LT. Colonel, 1946 (Box 17, Folder 77)
        - Naylor, William E. Jr., Captain, 1946 (Box 17, Folder 78)
        - Nelson, Russell M., LT. Colonel, 1946 (Box 17, Folder 79)
        - Pack, Charles M., LT, Colonel, 1946 (Box 17, Folder 80)
        - Papen, Bernard R., LT. Colonel, 1946 (Box 17, Folder 81)
        - Pearson, James P. Jr., LT, Colonel, 1946 (Box 17, Folder 82)
        - Rickenbaugh, Carl L., LT. Colonel, 1946 (Box 17, Folder 83)
        - Rude, Walter A., LT. Colonel, 1946 (Box 17, Folder 84)
        - Sackton, Frank J. Colonel, 1946 (Box 17, Folder 85)
        - Schafer, Remond, LT. Colonel, 1946 (Box 17, Folder 86)
        - Schofield, Frank C., Jr., Major, 1946 (Box 17, Folder 87)
        - Sells, John K., Colonel, 1946 (Box 17, Folder 88)
        - Shunk, Peter W., Colonel, 1946 (Box 17, Folder 89)
        - Slater, Vernon, LT. Colonel, 1946 (Box 17, Folder 90)
        - Strother, Tom B., Major, 1946 (Box 17, Folder 91)
        - Summers, Thomas B., LT. Colonel, 1946 (Box 17, Folder 92)
        - Sykes, Orin R., LT. Colonel, 1946 (Box 17, Folder 93)
        - Tarter, Jerome, 1946 (Box 17, Folder 94)
        - Thayer, Elmer Bryant, Colbnel, 1946 (Box 17, Folder 95)
        - Thomas, Henry G., LT. Colonel, 1946 (Box 17, Folder 96)
        - Thompson, John A., LT. Colonel, 1946 (Box 17, Folder 97)
        - Troup, Malcom G., LT. Colonel, 1946 (Box 17, Folder 98)
        - Van Vliet, John N. Jr., Colonel, 1946 (Box 17, Folder 99)
        - Willets, David L., LT. Colonel, 1946 (Box 17, Folder 100)
        - Wilson, Leroy C., Colonel, 1946 (Box 17, Folder 101)
      - Orientation material, 1946 (Box 18, Folder 102)
      - Outside speakers: War Department, 1946 (Box 18, Folder 103)
      - Reading assignments, 1946 (Box 18, Folder 104-106)
      - Roster, 1946 (Box 18, Folder 107)
      - Seating chart: room 217, undated (Box 18, Folder 108)
      - Schedules, 1945 (Box 18, Folder 109)
    - Class III
      - Academic information, 1946 (Box 18, Folder 110)
      - Attendance records, 1946 (Box 18, Folder 111)
      - Bibliography on China (supplementary), undated (Box 18, Folder 112)
      - Biographies, undated (Box 18, Folder 113)
      - Bursary appointments, 1946-1948 (Box 18, Folder 114)
      - Chinese Printing Office: orders, 1946 (Box 18, Folder 115)
      - Clerical Bureau bills, 1945-1946 (Box 18, Folder 116)
      - Conduct of school, Tentative outline for, undated (Box 18, Folder 117)
      - Costs, 1945 (Box 18, Folder 118)
      - Faculty correspondence
        - A- J, 1945-1946 (Box 18, Folder 119-121)
        - K-Y, 1945-1946 (Box 19, Folder 122-125)
      - Films: correspondence and memoranda, 1945 (Box 19, Folder 126)
      - Lectures: request for payments, 1946 (Box 19, Folder 127)
      - Library
        - Books: St. Anthony Hall, 1946 (Box 19, Folder 128)
        - Butler, Elizabeth, 1945-1946 (Box 19, Folder 129)
        - General, 1945-1946 (Box 19, Folder 130)
        - Lists: miscellaneous, 1946 (Box 19, Folder 131)
        - MacSporran, John S.: Librarian, 1946 (Box 19, Folder 132)
        - Periodicals on Far East: list, undated (Box 19, Folder 133)
      - Maps
        - Australia (outline), undated (Box 19, Folder 134)
        - China (outline), undated (Box 19, Folder 135)
        - Pacific Islands (outline), undated (Box 19, Folder 136)
        - Phillippines (outline), undated (Box 19, Folder 137)
        - U.S.S.R. (outline), undated (Box 19, Folder 138)